<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>WorldWind Server Kit/NASA WorldWind on NASA WorldWind</title>
    <link>https://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/serverkit/</link>
    <description>Recent content in WorldWind Server Kit/NASA WorldWind on NASA WorldWind</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 12:20:20 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/serverkit/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Features-WWSK/NASA WorldWind</title>
      <link>https://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/serverkit/features/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 12:21:37 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/serverkit/features/</guid>
      <description>Features WWSK&amp;rsquo;s features are built for data viewing. In addition to GeoServer&amp;rsquo;s general features, WWSK can export data as a GeoPackage, allowing the user to control its contents. Our most recently developed feature is the WorldWind Viewer, which lets you see your data in the context of Earth.
General Features  Understands multiple data formats such as Shapefiles, GeoTIFFS, GeoPackages, and GDAL formats Serves and shares data with clients Accesses data from remote services, acting as a proxy Uses an integrated GeoWebCache for improved client performance  WorldWind Explorer  Allows you to see your data in the context of a globe Visualizes all the layers and layer groups that you&amp;rsquo;ve defined on one terrain Understands and leverages your GeoServer&amp;rsquo;s capabilities and strengths&amp;ndash;no configuration required  GeoPackage Capabilities  Export your data as a GeoPackage Exported raster GeoPackages contain a collection of prerendered tiles User-controlled content (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Get Started-WWSK/NASA WorldWind</title>
      <link>https://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/serverkit/get-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Sep 2017 12:21:14 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://worldwind.arc.nasa.gov/serverkit/get-started/</guid>
      <description>Get Started Build WWSK uses Apache Maven for a build system. To build WWSK and its dependencies, run maven from the root of the WWSK repository:
$ mvn clean install  Run Depending on your personal preference, there are several ways to run WWSK.
 Deploy a standalone WWSK distribution Deploy a WAR file Run in NetBeans Run in Jetty from Maven Deploy a binary distribution  Detailed instructions for each of these options are available on GitHub.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>